I've been using the iron bull 10 mm
premium lifting belt for the past few
weeks and my favorite things about it
are the fact that you can choose between
a 3in or 4-in wide profile the Buckle
right here is in fact adjustable and
then honestly just the fact that it is a
fully leather build and it does have
that 10 mm thickness gives you a really
nice stiff external source for your core
muscles to brace against if you're
looking for a new lifting belt to add to
your gym bag you might have just found
your solution let's get to this
review
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the Barb and garage gym and for today's
video I've got the 10 mm premium lifting
belt from Iron Bull in this video today
we're going to talk about a lot of stuff
but specifically we're going to talk
about some money some pros and cons that
you might experience with this belt and
then of course who should or maybe
should not purchase it now before I do
that if you don't already know we've
reviewed a whole lot of lifting belts on
barb. comom we went ahead and made a
best list so if you want to check that
out all you got to do is search barvin
best lifting belt it's going to pull
right up for you and you can find out
for yourself which ones we like the
[Music]
best all right so before I start talking
about what I really like about this belt
I just just want to take a second and
kind of talk about lifting belts from a
broad scope I guess you could say so
there's a lot of different belts that
are out there obviously you know once
again this is a fully leather belt that
10 mm thickness this is perfect for
powerlifting you know especially the big
three squat well not really bench but
Squat and deadlift right and if you're
you know an Olympic lifter CrossFit
style lifter you're probably going to be
better off targeting you know a nylon
belt cuz it's it's going to allow you to
be more mobile within your lifts and
then you know there's different styles
of leather belts as well where they kind
of taper down in the front some of them
are thicker you know wider than this one
right here and then there's also hybrid
belts as well that are you know a
mixture of nylon and Leather So really
you know when it comes to finding the
right belt for you it really just boils
down to your specific style of training
so definitely keep that in mind you know
not all belts are you know the same
they're not all going to you know serve
you the same and and be perfect across
all of your lifts now the purpose of an
actual weightlifting belt is to help
increase your intraabdominal pressure
and allow you to brace those core
muscles against an external Source the
belt right here and that's going to be
perfect you know for especially heavy
weight whenever you're lifting some
heavy weight but also just to prevent
injury or maybe if you have an injury so
now that we kind of just you laid it out
on the table really quick let's expand
on what I like about this belt and
really you know this is perfect for
powerlifting that 10 mm thickness and
the fact that it is fully leather it
really just like I said earlier it
really creates creates a stiff and rigid
belt and it's going to be perfect for
those power lifts also really enjoy this
lever stainless steel lever right here
it's got these teeth prongs whatever you
want to call it and they're really going
to you know stay secure in the belt
right here and the belt's just not going
to come off as you're lifting which is
very very good thing I also really love
how you have all these different
adjustment points right here for the
actual lever so that way you know you
can get that nice snug fit whenever you
go to lift now this is the 4in wide 4in
profile belt there's also a 3-in version
that I was talking about that's really
nice too because you know a lot of times
with you know a 4-in belt sometimes for
people it kind of digs into your ribs
and it makes it uncomfortable for you to
lift so the fact that you have the
option to go after a 3-in one is pretty
sweet now this belts about 175 bucks
which is a pretty solid price tag you
know compared to other you know high
quality belts like this but that doesn't
necessarily mean it's going to fall
within everybody's budget so that might
be a reason for for you not to buy it
this also isn't going to be very
versatile right so this belt is
primarily meant for powerlifting so if
you're somebody who you know does more
than just powerlifting you'll either
have to you know go get two belts or
maybe just go find yourself a hybrid
belt like I was talking about earlier to
you know kind of match with your lifting
keep that in mind right there and then
lastly you know if you do go for the 4in
belt like I have right here just just
remember that it might dig into your
ribs a little bit as you're going to do
those squats and that might just be a
little bit uncomfortable for
[Music]
you already touched on it but once again
this 10 mm premium lifting belt from
Iron bu is going to run you right around
1075 bucks now I personally think it's
worthy of that price tag you know this
build is really nice and then the lever
Buckle is steel stainless steel so it's
really high quality as well if you want
to save some money though there's some
other options you might want to explore
one that comes to mind is the gym Reaper
10 mm lever belt it's about 120 bucks
right now maybe 125 that's a really
solid belt as well now I personally like
this one better but you know to to each
their own now another thing here is
really the main selling point with this
one kind of driving that price tag is
this stainless steel lever right so if
you want to stick with iron B they have
you know a couple other options that are
cheaper one that comes to mind is the 7
mm belt so it tapers in the front and
it's got you two prongs that you use
instead of a lever and they also have
some 10 mm belts that also use dual
prongs that's about 90 to 100 bucks so
it's really you know just on it comes
down to your personal
budget all right so with this belt you
have a buffalo hide exterior with a
suede interior so that suede's going to
be relatively comfortable on bare skin
also it's also going to have a little
bit of moisture wicking if if you tend
to sweat when you're working out that's
going to be a nice thing for you it's
only available in Black keep that in
mind but black goes with everything
right it's going to match all all of
your Gym gear and then this stainless
steel Buckle just really high quality
it's going to last you a long time it's
you know pretty durable right there now
this belt is available from extra small
to
4XL so ironbolt has a very helpful
sizing chart but what you need to do
whenever you go to size for your
specific belt is measure around your
belly button because that's where the
middle of the belt is going to be B
basically just match up where you
measure where you fall within that range
with the sizing chart and you're going
to be good to go remember this is the
one I have right here is 4 in wide the
profile there's also that 3in wide
profile if you find you know 4 in to be
a little bit too wide for you and lastly
something that I think is really cool
with this belt is that it's certified by
all these federations right here so that
way if you're a competitor you can
absolutely use it during your next
[Music]
competition
okay so remember with this belt you do
have that Buffalo exterior right here
Buffalo hide exterior and I really you
know I'm really big on this stainless
steel lever you know you got these
little prongs right here they're going
to fit nicely in these hooks in these
excuse me in these holes and it's simply
just not going to come off of you
whatsoever so on the inside right here
you know this is suede it's really it's
pretty pretty comfortable on your skin
and remember I talked about how you can
adjust that lever right so you got all
these holes right here this is not you
know limited to just this belt this is
the case with all lever belts but this
is awesome because it's going to allow
you to really find that perfect fit for
your body specifically right now you
also have this 4-in wide profile
remember there is that 3-in wide one if
you find this to be a little bit too
wide for you and a little bit
uncomfortable so it's nice you have a
little bit of variety now when it comes
to actually you know using it properly
and putting the belt on and everything
remember you measure around your belly
button because because that's where the
belt goes right around your core right
so just go ahead toss it around right
there put those in and then you just
pull back right here and it's not you
know it's nice and snug now cool thing
about lever belts in general is that you
can just pop that out and it's not
coming off of you you know so you can
take your brake in between your sets you
don't have to take it off completely
which is nice now a problem that people
face with lifting belts is not using
them the right way okay so a lot of
times people will
make the belt super tight and that
doesn't allow you to really take a deep
breath and you know expand your core so
what you want to be able to do is fit a
finger in between the belt and your
stomach right there and then whenever
you go to breathe you don't want to
breathe vertically when I when I say
vertically you don't want to you know
everything expand up you want to expand
your stomach so you want to breathe out
and then hold that abdominal pressure up
against the belt right there that way
you can really get you know as much
stability I guess you could say as
possible and when you're able to do that
properly that's where you're really
going to experience the benefits of
using a lifting belt okay so when we
talk about you know who should or maybe
shouldn't purchase this belt it's a
whole lot of personal preference going
on all right but first of all if you are
in fact you know a competitor and you're
looking for a certified belt for sport I
think this is a really good option for
you to consider now if you're a
powerlifter this is also going to be
great for you but
if you're not a powerlifter you don't
have you know a super heavy emphasis in
that maybe you sprinkle it in you
sprinkle in some other styles of
workouts you know CrossFit you know
Olympic weightlifting all of that yes
it's still going to work for you for
those powerlifting movements but if
you're doing those other ones you're
going to want to Target you know a nylon
belt and might be better for you to just
go ahead and get that nylon belt
especially if powerlifting is really not
your thing also budget you have if you
have the budget for it you know I think
this is worth that price tag like I said
there's other belts you can go and find
that are you know still really nice but
they're going to save you anywhere from
50 to you know maybe even closer to $100
definitely you know it is what it is
right you get what you pay for now
another thing here is the actual profile
right so if you don't like the 4-in wide
profile you feel like it digs into your
stomach your ribs then definitely go
after that 3-in wide
[Music]
one all right well that's a wrap for
today's review over the iron bull 10 mm
premium lifting belt this is my favorite
belt on the market at the moment it you
know the 10 mm thickness is perfect for
those power lifts 4-in wide profile
really gives you a solid surface area
for your core to brace against and
honestly you know once again this
stainless steel lever right here is just
going to allow it to stay nice and tight
against your body thanks for watching
everybody I hope this video was really
helpful and that I was able to break
down everything there is to know about
this belt as always stay posted for my
next video but for now head over to
barb. comom cuz we have a full written
article about this belt that I think
you're going to find to be pretty
helpful all you got to do is search
barbend Iron bull 10 mm premium lifting
belt review and it's going to pull right
up for you you can read over everything
we discussed today I'll catch yall next
time
[Music]
he